<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<company>
  <title>Chibifire.com (Pronounced as chee-bee-fire)</title>
  <based-in>Canada</based-in>
  <founding-date>2004</founding-date>
  <website>https://chibifire.com</website>

  <press-contact>ernest.lee@chibifire.com</press-contact>

  <analytics>G-4MM20XCEW7</analytics>

  <address>
    <line>YVR (Vancouver)</line>
    <line>British Columbia</line>
    <line>Canada</line>
  </address>

  <socials>
    <social>
      <name>Github @fire</name>
      <link>https://github.com/fire</link>
    </social>
    <social>
      <name>Twitter @iFiery</name>
      <link>https://twitter.com/iFiery</link>
    </social>
    <social>
      <name>V-Sekai Discord</name>
      <link>https://discord.gg/7BQDHesck8</link>
    </social>
  </socials>

  <description>
    Meet Ernest (iFire) Lee, a passionate developer based in Canada. Specializing in emerging technologies like game engines, particularly the Godot Engine, he plays a pivotal role in maintaining its glTF 3D pipeline. This includes managing both exporting and importing functionalities. He also works closely with the OMIGROUP to ensure metaverse interoperability and maintain an importer for the portable avatar format VRM in the Godot Engine.
  </description>
  <histories>
    <history>
      <header>Khronos Independent Contributor - 3D Formats | 2023 - present</header>
    </history>
    <history>
      <header>V-Sekai Social VR | 2021 - present</header>
    </history>
    <history>
      <header>Open Metaverse Interoperability Group Founding Member | 2022 - present</header>
    </history>
    <history>
      <header>Godot Engine Foundation - Full-time Contractor | 2023 Dec - 2024 May</header>
    </history>
    <history>
      <header>Khronos Advisor - 3D Formats | 2021 - 2023</header>
    </history>
    <history>
      <header>Artificial Intelligence Tools | 2023 April - 2023 August</header>
    </history>
    <history>
      <header>Unreal Engine 5 Development | 2022 September - 2022 November</header>
    </history>
    <history>
      <header>Godot Engine | 3D Asset Pipeline, Animations and others. | 2017 - present</header>
    </history>
    <history>
      <header>Godot Engine Development | 2018 Dec - 2022</header>
    </history>
    <history>
      <header>1st Place | Unity vs Unreal vs Godot: The Threeway Battle (Season 2) | 2018</header>
      <text>Stern Flowers won first place using Godot Engine.</text>
    </history>
    <history>
      <header>Offworld Industries | Publisher Developer Operations | 2018</header>
      <text>Helped Periscope Games use Offworld Core as a Unreal Engine plugin. Also adminstrated Perforce version control and continously delivered (CICD) the game project Post Scriptum.</text>
    </history>
    <history>
      <header>Offworld Industries | Developer Operations | 2016 - 2018</header>
      <text>Continuously delivered (CICD) Squad, handled Unreal Engine 4 upgrades, managed Perforce version control and administrated information technologies.</text>
    </history>
    <history>
      <header>Mektek Studios | Stompy Bot | Systems Professional | 2014 - 2016</header>
      <text>Build systems on Heavy Gear Assault.</text>
    </history>
  </histories>

  <additionals>
    <additional>
      <title>Godot 4.4, A unified experience</title>
      <link>https://godotengine.org/releases/4.4/</link>
      <description>Look forward to plenty of quality of life improvements hidden within this release. Faster load speeds, reduced stutter, streamlined processes — spotting all the optimizations that have been applied in the background will take some time. On top of that, long-awaited comfort features like embedded game windows and interactive in-game editing will feel more in line with other software on the market, making transitioning between them an even smoother experience. The editor overhaul alone takes up a big chunk of this release, after all.</description>
    </additional>
    <additional>
      <title>Adding CSG Manifold to Godot Engine 4.4</title>
      <link>https://godotengine.org/article/dev-snapshot-godot-4-4-dev-6</link>
      <description>In April 2022, while browsing Y Combinator News, a Google developer released a new GitHub project, https://github.com/elalish/manifold, focused on mesh booleans for 3D manufacturing. This offered a significant departure from traditional NURBS-based methods. The innovation promised that if a mesh were manifold, it would remain manifold through operations like addition, subtraction, and overlap, which, according to college courses on mesh constructive solid geometry (CSG), was foundational for creating manufacturable objects.
By May 2022, I had a prototype up and running, albeit with 300,000 lines of code that contained several bugs, which left me feeling demotivated. Over the following months, I collaborated with the manifold team to eliminate dependencies, ultimately removing the last one—TBB, which allowed for CPU core utilization—making it optional.
By July 2024, the code was functional but still had five significant bugs, and it was merged into the Godot engine in November 2024. This merge caused substantial issues, specifically breaking version 4.4 dev 6. Despite the struggles, the line count for the manifold CSG had reduced to 20,000 lines. Now, the manifold site lists integration with various platforms, including Godot, Babylon.js, and several CAD software solutions.</description>
    </additional>
    <additional>
      <title>GDC 2024: Retrospective</title>
      <link>https://godotengine.org/article/gdc-2024-retrospective/</link>
      <description>The team has returned from GDC, and it's time to share the experiences and memories made. We hope our absence wasn't too hard on you!</description>
    </additional>
    <additional>
      <title>Introducing the improved ufbx importer in Godot 4.3</title>
      <link>https://godotengine.org/article/introducing-the-improved-ufbx-importer-in-godot-4-3/</link>
      <description>Thanks to a very welcome contribution by Samuli Raivio (bqqbarbhg) and Ernest Lee (fire), Godot 4.3 now includes native .fbx support. This was made possible using Samuli’s free and open-source ufbx single-file .fbx library. The ufbx importer will be used by default for all newly imported .fbx files in Godot 4.3.</description>
    </additional>
    <additional>
      <title>Godot Has A New FBX Importer... And It's FASSSSSST!</title>
      <link>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TGszmac4Y2k</link>
      <description>In the forthcoming Godot 4.3 release, a significant new feature is being introduced - FBX support. You might be thinking, "But Mike, doesn't Godot already have FBX support?" Yes, it does. However, this one is different in three ways...</description>
    </additional>
    <additional>
      <title>Introducing Godot Sandbox</title>
      <link>https://github.com/libriscv/godot-sandbox</link>
      <description>In-editor scripting and sandboxing for Godot </description>
    </additional>
    <additional>
      <title>Godot Foundation Update 2023</title>
      <link>https://godotengine.org/article/godot-foundation-update-2023/</link>
      <description>The past year has been a landmark one for the Godot Foundation.</description>
    </additional>
    <additional>
      <title>Introducing the Godot glTF2 Scene exporter</title>
      <link>https://godotengine.org/article/introducing-the-godot-gltf-2-0-scene-exporter</link>
      <description>We hope that this makes our lives better with asset pipelines for 3D</description>
    </additional>
    <additional>
      <title>V-Sekai Social VR</title>
      <description>V-Sekai is a community of enthusiasts building a next-generation social and #gaming VR #platform powered by the Godot Engine.</description>
      <link>https://github.com/V-Sekai</link>
    </additional>
    <additional>
      <title>Open Metaverse Interoperability</title>
      <description>Protocols for interoperable virtual worlds</description>
      <link>https://github.com/omigroup/OMI</link>
    </additional>
    <additional>
      <title>Godot Engine</title>
      <description>An open-source game engine.</description>
      <link>https://godotengine.org</link>
    </additional>
  </additionals>
</company>
